Here in Örebro it is easy for you as a student to get a home.
Many students choose to live in the university area, close to campus.
Here there are several different student housing, in mixed sizes
Depending on how you want to live.
You can, among other things, live in corridor with shared kitchen and living room,
in a collective or in a separate apartment.
There are both student apartments but also ordinary rental properties
Around Örebro.
But how have the students gone about getting these apartments?
Here are some tips on how to get hold of a home
before or at the beginning of your studies.
You can stand in a residential queue
At, among other things, the municipal housing company Öbo
or with other private landlords.
In Örebro it is free to stand in a residential queue,
and you can queue up before you seek education,
So do it now.
Some private landlords do not use a queuing system
Without it, it is important to be first come, first served with a statement of interest.
On Örebro Municipality's website there is a list of all private landlords.
If you would probably not find any apartment in time until the course starts
So Öbo has a so -called housing guarantee.
This means that you who fail to find any apartment
may receive a time -limited agreement
So that you have somewhere to live during the first semester of your studies.
Read more about how the housing guarantee works at obo.se.